Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical and Electronics

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Engineering]

# VINAY KUMAR BOLLU (1) Featured

Application Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Project Management, SQL, Unix, PLSQL, Visual Studio, GIT, Oracle



Current Designation: Application Developer

Current Company: HCL Technologies

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Application Developer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Project Management, SQL, Unix, PLSQL, Visual Studio, GIT, Oracle

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

## Summary

Insightful experience in working as Senior Software Engineer with the ability to deliver against very challenging deadlines and have a flexible approach to the demands of the role

Proficient in SDLC and all phases of Application development with the working knowledge of UNIX commands Strong proficiency in languages such as PL/SQL, SQL, Unix and databases such as Oracle 11g and Oracle 12C Manual dexterity in coordinating with various teams like Deployment, Testing Team to speed up development process Good exposure on advanced topics Like Analytical Functions, Indexes

Strong aptitude in understanding of business processes with good experience in development

Experience with a good understanding of mainstream software development methodologies, values and procedures Effective interpersonal, presentation, communication skills with an ability to interact professionally with a diverse group of clients

## Work Experience

**HCL Technologies** as Application Developer Apr 2020 to Till Date

Responsibilities:

Worked as a PLSQL Developer and experience in creating Packages, Functions, Procedures, Records, Cursors, Collections and Complex SQLPL/SQL, Dynamic SQL programming skills.

Experience in Oracle database development, troubleshooting, Bug Fix and performance tuning of PL/SQL Responsible for requirement gathering, estimation, development, testing of PLSQL codes.

**DXC Technologies** as Application Developer Jan 2020 to Apr 2020

Responsibilities:

Working and supporting the ETL workflows using BODS and providing the production support for ETL jobs recovery and also proving hot fix to ETL work flows.

Developing and maintaining the new ETL workflows with meets the requirements and business logics.

#### Capgemini as Associate Consultant

Dec 2016 to Dec 2019

#### Responsibilities:

Spearhead, guide and coach the Mumbai Team including 3 members for Shipment Tracing Application.

Develop and maintain Shipment Tracing, Dock Reweigh, Enterprise billing system application.

Manage the on-call support for Line hall application.

Comfortable with conversing with stakeholders

Manage implementation of software engineering strategy

Identify and resolve issues or continuation of engineering activities

Identify and suggest improvements to the existing system and workflows

Involved explain plan and investigate the performance issues

Proactively drive innovation with new ideas and options made available by new technologies

Share knowledge and supervise more junior team members

#### Achievements:

Organized and conducted various knowledge transfer sessions for the team

Established Proficiency in creating packages, functions, procedures and triggers etc.

Performed database tuning to achieve up to 70% performance enhancement of the Reweigh application

Enhanced Reweigh application and performed optimization and reduced execution time by 50%

Key role in taking initiatives to execute projects on time and within budget

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical and Electronics Engineering) from CMR College of Engineering & Technology, Hyderabad in 2016

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
ORACLE 11G	
PL/SQL, SQL, Mongo DB, Unix	
Visual Studio, PL/SQL Developer	
Oracle SQL Developer	
SQL	
RDBMS	
Unix	
PLSQL	
Oracle SQL	
Oracle SQL Developer	

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Telugu				

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: OBC - non-creamy

Physically Challenged: No

US Work Status: Authorized to Work in the US

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time